舰长日志，星历3192.1
Captain's log, stardate 3192.1.
进取号正前往NGC 321星团
The Enterprise is en route to star cluster NGC 321.
任务：与当地文明
Objective: To open diplomatic relations
建立外交关系
with the civilisations known to be there.
我们向该星团的主要行星
We have sent a message to Eminiar VII,
伊米亚7号发送了讯息
principal planet of the star cluster,
向他们通告我们的友好目的
informing them of our friendly intentions.
现在在等待回复
We are awaiting an answer.
上尉，还没回复？
Nothing yet, lieutenant?
没有，舰长，呼叫频道已打开
Nothing, captain. Hailing frequencies are open.
舰长，你收到回复了吗？
Have you received an answer to your message yet, captain?
还没有，大使，我们还在等待
Nothing yet, ambassador. We're awaiting a reply.
据我们所知这是他们第一次收到信息
Today is the first time we've had any evidence they've picked up our signal.
舰长，收到来自伊米亚7号的讯息
Captain, message coming in from Eminiar VII.
- 舰长，是代码710 - 你确定？
- Sir, it's code 710. - Are you sure?
没错，而且在不断重复
Positive. It repeats over and over again.
那是什么意思？
Is that supposed to mean something?
代码710的意思是在任何情况下
Code 71 0 means under no circumstances
我们都不得接近该行星，特殊情况也不行
are we to approach that planet. No circumstances whatsoever.
你必须忽略该信号，舰长
You will disregard that signal, captain.
- 福克斯，那是他们的行星 - 舰长，过去20年中
- Mr. Fox, it is their planet. - Captain, in the past 20 years
我们已在该象限损失了数千生命
thousands of lives have been lost on this quadrant,
如果联邦在此建有条约港，这些生命就能获救
lives that could have been saved if the Federation had a treaty port here.
我们必须建立港口，这是我的使命
We mean to have that port, and I'm here to get it.
要是忽略代码710，你很可能会让我们
By disregarding code 710, you might well involve us
卷入一场星际战争
in an interplanetary war.
- 我准备赌上一把 - 是吗？
- I'm quite prepared to take that risk. - You are?
我得为这艘星舰，还有船员考虑
I'm thinking about this ship, my crew.
舰长，我有我的使命，而你有你的任务
I have my orders, captain, and now you have yours.
你必须保持航线
You will proceed on course,
进入行星轨道，剩下的交给我
achieve orbit status and just leave the rest to me.
你应该清楚我有权下达命令
You're well aware that my mission gives me the power of command.
现在听令
I now exercise it.
你必须保持航线，这是我的命令
You will proceed on course. That's a direct order.
关于代码710，我建议您…
In view of code 710, captain, may I suggest--?
我明白，史波克
Yes, Mr. Spock.
这是舰长，黄色警戒
This is the captain. Condition, yellow alert.
相位炮小组待命，启动偏导盾
Phaser crews, stand by. Deflector shields up.
先生们，我们要闯进去了
We're going in, gentlemen.
希望能相安无事，但不管怎么样…
Peacefully, I hope, but peacefully or not...
…我们都要进去
...we're going in.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：风梦秋 Nick
校对：喜马拉雅
第一季第二十三集
末日决战的滋味
舰长日志，星历3192.5
Captain's log, stardate 3192.5.
已进入伊米亚7号的标准轨道
Now in standard orbit around planet Eminiar VII.
我的命令非常简单
My orders are clear.
我们必须不惜一切代价建立外交关系
We must establish diplomatic relations at all cost.
准备传送至行星表面
Preparing to beam down to planet's surface.
我们对他们的了解非常匮乏，他们的文明相当先进
We know very little about them. Their civilisation is advanced.
他们几世纪前就开始星际飞行
They've had space flight for several centuries,
但从未跨出本星系
but they've never ventured beyond their own solar system.
当我们50多年前跟他们接触时
When first contacted more than 50 years ago,
伊米亚7号正跟最近的邻居交战
Eminiar VII was at war with its nearest neighbour.
还有别的吗？
Anything else?
提交该报告的地球探险队未能完成任务
The Earth expedition making the report failed to return from its mission.
联邦星舰勇士号
The USS Valiant.
被列为失踪
Listed as missing in space.
寇克，你一个人下去？
Kirk, what's this about you going alone?
不，大使，我会带上安保人员
Not alone, Mr. Ambassador. I'm taking some security people with me.
- 交涉可是我的特权… - 我不能冒险传送你下去
- It is my prerogative-- - I can't risk beaming you down there
除非我知道你会受到什么招待
until I know what kind of reception you're going to receive.
我得为你的安全负责，先生，这是我的任务
Your safety is my responsibility. Those are my orders, sir.
- 史波克 - 传送室准备就绪，舰长
- Mr. Spock. - Transporter Room standing by.
- 什么坐标？ - 我们已选择了一个地点
- What coordinates? - We have selected a site which,
根据交通情况看靠近政府机构
from the traffic, would seem to be near an official establishment.
- 最后的感应器读数如何？ - 没有针对我们的敌对举动
- Final sensor readings? - No hostility directed toward us.
根本没有引起他们注意，这有点奇怪
No apparent notice taken of us at all, which seems strange.
我们进入轨道时他们做了扫描，显然他们知道我们来了
They did scan us when we assumed orbit. Obviously, they know we're here.
星舰防御情况如何？
Ship's defences?
护盾已关闭，所有单位处于警戒状态, 舰长
Screens down, but all defensive details on general alert status, captain.
很好
Good.
登陆小队将到军械库领取I型相位手枪
Landing party will pick up phaser number ones from the arsenal.
- 把它们藏好，史考特 - 是，长官
- Keep them inconspicuous. Mr. Scott? - Yes, sir?
由你接管星舰，在我回来前照看好她
The ship is yours. Take care of her until I come back.
是，长官，一路顺风
Aye, aye, sir. And have a bonny trip.
我们尽力而为，出发
We'll do our best. Let's go.
他们会在那里物化成形
They will materialise there.
牢记你们的指令，照章办事，仅此而已
Remember your instructions. They are to be treated correctly, nothing more.
我是星舰进取号的舰长詹姆士·寇克
I'm Captain James T. Kirk of the starship Enterprise,
代表星际联邦
representing the United Federation of Planets.
我知道，我是梅娅3
I know. I am Mea 3.
你们的技术很不错
I congratulate you on your instrumentation.
直接来到了指挥部
You've come directly to the Division of Control.
请跟我来
If you'll follow me, please.
- 舰长，我希望… - 请说
- Captain, I wish... - Yes?
- 你们已被警告过不要过来 - 我奉命前来
- You were warned not to come here. - I had orders to come here.
为什么你们不让我们接近？
Why did your people tell us to stay away?
- 为你们的安全考虑，舰长 - 这里没有危险
- It was for your own safety, captain. - I see no danger here.
这里确实有危险
The danger exists.
多说无益，既然来了
Nevertheless, you are here.
不好好招待你们是说不过去的
It would be morally incorrect to do less than extend our hospitality.
阿南7及最高议会的其他成员都在等你
Anan 7 and members of the High Council await you.
请往这边走
If you will come this way, please.
我是寇克舰长，这是我的大副史波克先生
I'm Captain Kirk. This is my first officer, Mr. Spock.
加洛韦上尉，奥斯本上尉，田村文书
Lieutenants Galloway, Osborne, Yeoman Tamura.
欢迎来到伊米亚7号
Welcome to Eminiar VII.
那么，舰长，我们有什么可效劳的？
Well, captain, what can we do for you?
我的任务是在我们双方之间
My mission is to establish diplomatic relations
建立外交关系
between your people and mine.
这是不可能的
That is impossible.
- 你能解释一下原因吗？ - 是因为战争
- Would you mind telling me why? - Because of the war.
你们还在交战？
You're still at war?
这场战争已经持续了500年
We have been at war for 500 years.
那你们也掩盖地太好了，史波克？
You conceal it very well. Mr. Spock?
先生，我们全面扫描过你们的星球
Sir, we have completely scanned your planet.
我们发现它高度进化，物质繁荣
We find it highly advanced, prosperous in a material sense,
人民生活舒适而且环境优美
comfortable for your people and peaceful in the extreme.
你却说在交战，根本就没有战争迹象
Yet you say you are at war. There is no evidence of this.
我们的人口伤亡情况是
Casualties among our civilian population
每年有1到3百万人死于敌人直接攻击
total from 1 to 3 million dead each year from direct enemy attack.
这是我们让你保持距离的理由之一
That is one reason, captain, why we told you to stay away.
只要你的星舰停留在我们的轨道上，它就处于极度危险
As long as your ship is orbiting our planet, it is in severe danger.
你们的敌人是谁？
With whom are you at war?
我们星系的第三行星，梵帝卡
The third planet in our system, called Vendikar.
最初是我们的殖民地，现在成了无情的敌人
Originally settled by our people and now a ruthless enemy.
技术非常先进
Highly advanced technologically.
请见谅
Please excuse me.
梵帝卡发起了进攻
Vendikar is attacking.
梅娅，照顾好我们的客人
Mea, care for our guests.
- 奇怪 - 不是一般地奇怪
- Strange. - To say the least.
- 不会持续很久的 - 你们不用找地方躲避吗？
- It will not last long. - Don't you take shelter?
- 没有避难所，舰长 - 这种攻击经常发生吗？
- There is no shelter, captain. - Are these attacks frequent?
哦，是的，而我们会立即反击
Oh, yes. And we will retaliate immediately.
怎么了？
What is it?
一次打击，就在这座城市
A hit, right here in the city.
你有听到爆炸声吗，史波克？
Do you hear any explosions, Mr. Spock?
没有，舰长，田村文书？
None, captain. Yeoman Tamura?
- 长官？ - 三录仪读数
- Sir? - Tricorder readings.
任何形式的辐射干扰
Radiation disturbances of any kind.
什么都没有，长官，毫无迹象
Nothing, sir. No evidence.
梅娅，如果这是一次攻击
Mea, if this is an attack,
请允许我问一下敌人使用了什么武器？
may I ask what weapons the enemy is using?
热核弹，在攻击目标上方物化成形
Fusion bombs, materialised by the enemy over their targets.
- 寇克呼叫舰桥，史考特？ - 这是史考特，舰长
- Kirk to bridge. Scotty? - Scott here, captain.
感应器在扫描行星表面吗？
Scanners operative on the planet surface?
当然有，长官，按照你的命令
Of course, sir. As per orders.
有什么异常吗？
Anything unusual?
没有，长官，很平静
Nothing, sir. All quiet.
谢谢，寇克完毕
Thank you. Kirk out.
看，阿南
Look, Anan.
对，我看到了，我们警告过他们了
Yes, I see it. They were warned.
就像50年前一样
Just as it happened 50 years ago.
通知安全支队，可能会需要他们
Alert a security detachment. They may be needed.
一次凶猛的攻击，极具破坏性
It was a vicious attack, extremely destructive.
幸运的是我们有坚固的防御
Fortunately, our defences are firming.
但我们的伤亡很大，非常大
But our casualties are high, very high.
先生，我一直跟我的星舰保持联系
Sir, I have been in contact with my ship,
他们一直在监控整个星球
which has had this entire planet under surveillance.
在这整个…
All during this...
…所谓的攻击期间我们都在监视
...so-called attack of yours, we have been monitoring you.
没有发现攻击，没有爆炸，没有辐射
There's been no attack, no explosions, no radiations,
没有任何骚乱
no disturbances whatsoever.
你们到底是在玩什么把戏…
If this is some sort of game you're playing--
这不是游戏，舰长
This is no game, captain.
有超过50万人刚刚被杀死
Half a million people have just been killed.
- 启动攻击装置，萨 - 是，议员
- Activate the attack units, Sar. - Yes, councilman.
马上发动反击
Launch immediate counterattack.
计算机，舰长
Computers, captain.
他们全面使用计算机来进行战争
They fight their war with computers, totally.
对了，当然
Yes, of course.
计算机不会杀死50万人民
Computers don't kill a half a million people.
死亡已经被登记，当然，他们有24小时来报到
Deaths have been registered. Of course, they have 24 hours to report.
- 报到？ - 向我们的裂解机器报到
- To report? - To our disintegration machines.
你得理解，舰长
You must understand, captain,
我们的战争已经持续了500年
we have been at war for 500 years.
在一般情况下，没有文明能够幸免
Under ordinary conditions, no civilisation could withstand that.
但是我们找到了解决办法
But we have reached a solution.
那么梵帝卡人的攻击只是理论上的？
Then the attack by Vendikar was theoretical?
哦，不是，相当真实
Oh, no. Quite real.
每次攻击都经过了精确的计算
An attack is mathematically launched.
在上次进攻中我失去了我的妻子
I lost my wife in the last attack.
我们的文明得以保存
Our civilisation lives.
人民阵亡但文化继续
The people die, but our culture goes on.
你该不是说…
You mean to tell me...
…你的人民接到通知后
...your people just walk into a disintegration machine
就老老实实地走进裂解机器？
when they're told to?
我们都有高度的使命感，舰长
We have a high consciousness of duty, captain.
这确实有些符合科学逻辑
There is a certain scientific logic about it.
我很高兴你能认同
I'm glad you approve.
我并不是认同
I do not approve.
- 我只是能够理解 - 很好
- I understand. - Good.
你们记得我警告过不要来
Then you will recall I warned you not to come here.
你们选择无视警告
You chose to ignore my warning.
我很抱歉，但它还是发生了
I'm sorry, but it's happened.
- 你在说什么？ - 一旦你们的星舰进入我们的轨道
- What has happened? - Once your ship was in orbit
它就成了一个合法的目标
about our planet, it became a legitimate target.
它在一次三钴卫星爆炸中被算作已被摧毁
It has been classified destroyed by a tricobalt satellite explosion.
你们星舰上所有人员要在24小时内
All persons aboard your ship have 24 hours
前往我们的裂解机器报到
to report to our disintegration machines.
为了确保他们老实合作，我已下令将你，舰长
In order to ensure their cooperation, I have ordered you, captain,
和你的手下扣留，直到你的船员投降
and your party held in custody until they surrender.
有可能的话，我们会放过星舰，舰长
If possible, we shall spare your ship, captain.
但它的船员和乘客都死了
But its passengers and crew are already dead.
舰长日志，延迟记录
Captain's log, delayed.
处于伊米亚7号环绕轨道上的进取号
The Enterprise, in orbit about Eminiar VII,
在计算机演算的怪异战争中
has been declared a casualty
成了牺牲品
of an incredible war fought by computers.
我和登陆小队虽然不算在
I and my landing party, though apparently not included
进取号战亡人员之列
as casualties aboard the Enterprise,
但被扣留在该行星
are confined on the planet's surface,
在等待着什么？
awaiting what?
我被派来了解你们有什么需求
I have been sent to ask if you require anything.
我们有很多需求，我想跟阿南7谈谈
We require a great deal. I wish to speak to Anan 7.
他在忙着整理伤亡人员清单
He is busy coordinating casualty lists.
如果他不过来跟我谈谈
He'll have more casualty lists than he knows what to do with
新增的伤亡名单会把他埋起来
if he doesn't get in here and talk to me.
你怎么就不明白？我们现在的使命…
Don't you understand? Our duty now--
你的使命可不包括走进一台裂解器化为乌有
Your duty doesn't include stepping into a disintegrator and disappearing.
恐怕那也是我的使命，舰长
I'm afraid mine does, captain.
我也被宣告为一名伤亡者
I, too, have been declared a casualty.
我必须在明天中午前到裂解器报到
I must report to a disintegrator by noon tomorrow.
对你来说这么重要？
Is that all it means to you?
报到送死？
To report and die?
我像你一样珍惜自己的性命，舰长
My life is as dear to me as yours is to you, captain.
- 那你怎么能接受？ - 你不明白吗？
- But how can you stand--? - Don't you see?
如果我拒绝报到，其他人也会
If I refuse to report, and others refuse,
梵帝卡人别无选择只能使用真正的武器
then Vendikar would have no choice but to launch real weapons.
我们为了自卫也只能效法
We would have to do the same to defend ourselves.
那就不只是人民伤亡了
More than people would die then.
整个文明都会被摧毁
A whole civilisation would be destroyed.
毫无疑问，你会发现我们的方法更优越
Surely, you can see that ours is the better way.
不，我不这么看
No. I don't see that at all.
这种方法我们已经使用了将近500年
It's been our way for almost 500 years.
我能给你提供什么吗？
Is there anything I can bring you?
有，阿南7
Yes. Anan 7.
我说，过了这么久他们应该有点消息了
I tell you, we should've heard something by now.
是，医生，应该是，可我们没有收到任何消息
Aye, doctor, that we should. But we haven't.
我们也无法把他们传送上来
And we cannot raise them.
如果他们碰到什么麻烦
Now, if there'd been trouble, they should've at least managed
- 至少能传个话 - 但我们不能这么干坐着
- to get word back to us. - Well, we can't just sit here.
你有什么建议？
What would you suggest?
我？我只是个医生，如果我是一线指挥官，我
Me? I'm a doctor. If I were an officer of the line, I--
- 你会命令我开火？ - 当然不
- Would you have me open fire? - Of course not.
史考特，来自舰长的讯息
Mr. Scott, message coming in from the captain.
- 我是史考特，舰长 - 好消息，史考特
- Scott here, captain. - Good news, Mr. Scott.
伊米亚人同意建立
The Eminians have agreed to the establishment
全面的常规外交关系
of full, normal, diplomatic relations.
福克斯听到这个消息会很高兴
Mr. Fox will be glad to hear about that.
他们还向全体船员发了邀请
They've also extended an invitation to all personnel
登陆进行上岸休假
to come ashore for shore leave.
他们保证船员们会过得很愉快
They've assured me that our people will have a wonderful time.
- 舰长？ - 是，史考特
- Captain? - Yes, Mr. Scott.
- 所有船员？ - 所有船员
- All personnel? - All personnel.
我们会传送训练过的伊米亚人接管星舰
We'll transport up trained Eminians to assume support positions.
这是我的命令，史考特
Those are my orders, Mr. Scott.
是，舰长
Aye, aye, captain.
我会马上开始组建登陆小队，史考特完毕
I'll start forming shore parties immediately. Scott out.
好吧，你怎么看？
Well, now, what do you think of that?
我不知道
I don't know.
我知道
Well, I do.
计算机，找到寇克舰长发回的最后一条讯息
Computer, last message received and recorded from Captain Kirk.
已就位
In place.
对它进行分析，问题：它是不是舰长的声音？
Run it through analyser. Question: Is it or is it not the captain's voice?
否定，逼真的复制品
Negative. A close copy.
- 来自语音复制器？ - 可能性98%
- A voice duplicator? - Ninety-eight percent probability.
好吧，伊米亚人抓住他们了，医生 现在他们想把我们骗下去
Well, they've got them, doctor. And now they're trying to get us.
你确定你能做到吗，史波克？
Are you sure you can do it, Mr. Spock?
瓦肯人天生能够远程移情，舰长
Limited telepathic abilities are inherent in Vulcanians, captain.
可能有用，可能没有
It may work, it may not.
你尽力而为吧
Do your best.
- 谢了，史波克 - 乐意效劳
- Thank you, Mr. Spock. - My pleasure.
我们现在怎么办，舰长？
What do we do now, captain?
我们找回通讯器，然后尝试联系进取号
We get our communicators back and try and contact the ship.
史波克，我们需要更多武器
Mr. Spock, we'll need more weapons.
我明白
I understand.
我们应争取手下留情，但如果不得不杀人…
We'll try to take it easy, but if we're forced to kill...
一个入口，舰长，但没有出口
An entrance, captain, but no exit.
他们走进去，但没有走出来
They go in, but they do not come out.
- 一台裂解机器 - 我猜也是
- A disintegration machine. - So I would assume.
梅娅
Mea.
你知道你在干什么吗？
What do you think you're doing?
- 我要进去-- - 你不能进去
- I'm-- I'm going-- - You're not going in there.
- 但我必须 - 不，你没必要
- But I must. - No, you're not.
求你了，没关系的，不用担心我
Please. It's all right. Don't worry about me.
史波克，那个守卫
Mr. Spock, that guard.
我会掩护你
I'll cover you.
先生，你肩头爬了一只多脚生物
Sir, there's a multi-legged creature crawling on your shoulder.
好了，你们快让开
All right, you people, clear out of the way.
噢，你在干什么？
Oh, what are you doing?
破坏那台机器
Throwing a monkey wrench into the machinery.
- 你不能这么做！ - 我已经做完了
- You can't do this! - I've done it.
来吧，让我们离开这里
Come on, let's get out of here.
联邦俘虏袭击警卫后逃跑了
The Federation prisoners have attacked their guard and escaped.
他们有武器
They are armed.
12号裂解站被摧毁了，议员
Disintegration station number 12 destroyed, councilman.
他们用的是裂解枪
Apparently by disrupter fire.
所有安全人员，联邦俘虏在逃
All security personnel, Federation prisoners have escaped.
必须抓到他们，他们有武器
They are to be found. They are armed.
如果他们抵抗，格杀勿论
If they resist, do what is necessary.
行星裂解炮组
Planetary disrupter banks,
计算环绕轨道上星舰的位置
calculate orbit of star cruiser now circling.
准备开火，最大能量
Stand by to fire, full power.
议员，行星裂解炮组锁定目标
Councilman, planetary disrupter banks locked onto target.
待命中
Standing by.
10秒后开火
In ten seconds, open fire.
摧毁星舰
Destroy the star cruiser.
这是议会的命令
Those are the orders of the Council.
星舰日志，星历3193.0
Ship's log, stardate 3193.0.
首席工程师史考特负责记录
Chief Engineer Scott recording.
舰长和大副没有登舰
The captain and first officer are overdue and missing
他们在伊米亚7号失踪
on the surface of Eminiar VII.
我已采取标准预防措施
I have taken standard precautionary measures
一边继续努力定位他们
while we continue our attempts to locate them.
所有岗位报告，偏导屏障能量全满
All stations reporting. Deflector screens rigged at full power.
相位炮小组到位，感应器读数为零
Phaser crews ready. Sensors reading zero.
- 修正，史考特？ - 是的，迪保罗
- Correction. Mr. Scott? - Yes, Mr. DePaul.
感应器读数刚刚破表
Sensor readings just shot off the scale.
噢，不好，他们在炮击我们
Oh, no. They're taking potshots at us.
- 护盾能顶住吗，迪保罗？ - 没问题，长官
- Holding, Mr. DePaul? - Screens firm, sir.
超高能量的音波，18的12次方分贝
Extremely powerful sonic vibrations, decibels 18 to the 12th power.
如果偏导屏障没有打开，我们现在已经被彻底分解了
If those screens weren't up, we'd be totally disrupted by now.
看来他们回答了我们的问题，史考特
Well, I guess that answers our questions, Mr. Scott.
- 他们不是特别友好，是吧？ - 对
- They're not very friendly, are they? - Aye.
但是我们的舰长和登陆小队成员怎么办？
But what about our captain and the landing party down there somewhere?
把他们救出来
We get them out.
除非他们能活着被我们找到，这个星球可不小
If they're alive and if we can find them. That's a big planet.
如果迫不得已，进取号能应付
Not too big for the Enterprise to handle, if it has to.
开着偏导盾，相位炮没法用最大火力
We can't fire full phasers with our screens up.
他们还在瞄准，不能关闭屏障
And we can't lower our screens with their disrupters on us.
当然，我可以喂他们几打光子鱼雷
Of course, I could treat them to a few dozen photon torpedoes.
你不能这么干，史考特
You'll do no such thing, Mr. Scott.
福克斯，我们正遭到攻击，他们想把我们打下去
Mr. Fox, we're under attack. They're trying to knock us down.
- 你已经采取了防御措施 - 当然，不过
- You have taken defensive measures. - Of course, but--
“不过”，没有什么“不过”
"But." There are no "buts."
很显然，这是场误会
Obviously, it's a misunderstanding,
而我的职责之一就是消除误会
and one of my jobs is to clear up misunderstandings.
- 他们抓住了舰长 - 我们没有证据
- They're holding our captain. - We have no proof of that.
我要负责这艘星舰的安全
I'm responsible for the safety of this ship.
我还要负责这次任务
And I'm responsible for the success of this mission.
那比这艘星舰更重要，明白吗？
And that's more important than this ship. Is that clear?
我们跑来跟他们建立外交关系
We came here to establish diplomatic relations with these people.
但他们却想交战，福克斯
But they're the ones looking for a fight, Mr. Fox.
这是一个外交事件
This is a diplomatic matter.
如果你查看舰队规章，会发现我的命令具有优先权
If you'll check your regulations, you'll find that my orders get priority.
我会试图跟行星当局沟通
I'll try to make contact with the planetary officials.
上尉，开启一个频道
Lieutenant, open up a channel and keep it open.
告诉他们准备接收我的一级优先讯息
Tell them to expect a priority-one message from me.
不得采取报复措施，先生们，这是我的命令
There will be no punitive measures, gentlemen. Those are my orders.
外交官
Diplomats.
据我所知，相位炮是最好的外交
The best diplomat I know is a fully activated phaser bank.
- 我们干嘛回来？ - 这会出乎他们意料
- Why did we come back here? - The last place they'll look for us
他们不会到这里找我们，把好门
is the place we escaped from. Cover the door.
舰长，你得让我离开，我的时限马上就到
Captain, you have got to let me go. My time is almost up.
- 你就这么渴望去死吗？ - 你不明白
- Are you that anxious to die? - You don't understand.
史波克，我们的小小袭击成果如何？
Mr. Spock, how did that little raid work out?
我们缴获了四把他们的裂解武器
We captured four of their disrupter-type weapons,
两套完整的男装，然后，还有最重要的
two complete outfits of male clothing and perhaps, most important of all,
一件通讯装置
one of their communication devices.
- 可以用它和母舰取得联系吗？ - 不行
- Will it reach the ship? - Not at this time.
它的通讯范围小于我们那套
Its range is restricted in comparison with ours.
我也许能更换配件，但需要时间
I may be able to alter its components, but it will take time.
去换吧，我们必须和星舰取得联系
Get to work on it. We've got to contact the ship.
梅娅，你来告诉我这栋建筑的构造
Mea, I want you to give me a complete layout of this building complex.
- 怎么才能到作战室？ - 不！
- How do I get to the War Room? - No!
听我说
Now, listen to me.
我想救你，还有数以百万像你这样的人
I'm trying to help you, to save your life and the lives of millions like you.
如果你帮我，我也许能做到
If you help me, maybe I can do it.
如果你不帮，不仅你会死
If you don't, you'll die.
我们都会死，而杀戮会继续，难道你喜欢战争？
We'll die, and the killing will go on. Or are you that fond of the war?
你想怎么做？
What are you going to do?
我们要设法阻止杀戮
We're going to try and stop the killing.
我们会尽力帮忙，相信我
We'll try to help. Believe me.
我相信你，但是…
I believe you. But...
让我知道我想知道的一切
Tell me what I want to know.
求你了
Please.
期限快到了
Time is running out.
我们无法摧毁那艘星舰
We have been unable to destroy the Earth ship.
还损失了一间裂解室
One of our disintegration chambers has been eliminated,
伤亡报到人数严重不足
and we have already fallen far behind in our quota.
事态严重，但我不知如何应对
This is a grave crisis, and I am at a loss to know how to proceed.
阿南，地球特使正在中心频道
The central channel, Anan.
进行紧急呼叫
The Earth ambassador is calling with an urgent message.
哪种行为更高尚？
What is the greater morality,
是诚实，还是能拯救我们性命的谎言？
open honesty or a deception which may save our lives?
让我和地球特使说
Put me through to the Earth ambassador.
频道接通了，特使先生
A channel is open, Mr. Ambassador.
你正在同阿南交谈
You will be speaking to Anan 7,
伊米亚联盟最高议会的首脑
head of the High Council of the Eminian Union.
阿南先生，我是罗伯特·福克斯
Mr. Anan, this is Robert Fox,
星际联邦的特使
Special ambassador for the United Federation of Planets.
与你通话是我的荣幸，特使先生
A great honour, Mr. Ambassador.
我们公开与你们接触
We have approached you openly,
希望能在你我人民之间
with the intent of establishing formal and friendly relations
建立正式友好的关系
between our peoples. But now,
但你却因为某些原因攻击了我们
for some reason, you have attacked us, and apparently,
还扣留了我们联邦的几位代表
you're holding several special representatives of our Federation.
这是误会，特使先生，我们正在打仗
A mistake, Mr. Ambassador. We are at war.
我们的感应器错误地以为你们的星舰会攻击我们
An error in our sensors indicated that your ship was about to attack us.
我将下令停止攻击
I'm giving orders that our attack be stopped.
而至于你们的代表
Now, as to your representatives,
我以伊米亚人的名义担保，他们很好
you have my sacred word as an Eminian that they are alive and well.
谢谢
Thank you.
我觉得这都是误会
I thought perhaps it was all a mistake.
史考特，裂解炮停止了攻击
Mr. Scott, disrupter beams are no longer hitting us.
维持现状，迪保罗
Maintain status, Mr. DePaul.
我们热切希望与你们建交，福克斯
We are most anxious to establish relations with you, Mr. Fox.
我们会安排与你们见面
We will make arrangements to receive you.
等他们的防护罩一消失就开火
The minute their screens are down, open fire.
遵命，议员
Yes, councilman.
我对之前的误会感到非常抱歉
I apologise deeply for the misunderstanding.
目前我们正处于艰难时期，希望你能理解
These are trying times for us, you understand.
我理解
I understand.
阿南先生，我希望会面时
Mr. Anan, I presume that
你能带上我们的舰长
you'll have our ship's captain on hand when I beam down.
我会的，先生，我向你保证
He will be there, sir. I give you my word.
我相信，从今天开始
I'm sure that, from this day forward,
你的星球和我们联邦之间将建立深厚友谊
your planet and our Federation will attain the deepest friendship.
我期待与你见面
I look forward to seeing you.
先生们，外交工作还是应该留给外交官
Diplomacy, gentlemen, should be a job left to diplomats.
现在，你应该把防护罩关掉
You will, of course, immediately resume a peaceful status.
不，我拒绝
No, sir. I will not.
你说什么？
What did you say?
除非舰长有令，否则我不会关掉防护罩
I'll not lower the screens. Not until the captain tells me to.
现在你得听我的
You are taking orders from me.
把防护罩关掉，不然你就是在抗令
You will lower the screens as a sign of good faith.
- 我有权… - 我知道你的权力
- My authority-- - I know about your authority,
但我不会关掉防护罩
but the screens stay up.
福克斯，他们伪造了舰长的信息
Mr. Fox, they faked a message from the captain,
他们对我们的星舰进行了攻击
they've launched an attack against our ship.
而你现在让我们信任他们？
Now you want us to trust them openly?
快点执行我的命令
I want you and expect you to obey my lawful orders.
不，先生，恕难从命
No, sir. I won't lower the screens.
你们这样违抗我的命令
Your refusal to comply with my orders
会严重威胁这次任务！
has endangered the entire success of this mission!
我可以将你们流放
I can have you sent to a penal colony for this.
没错，长官，但我不会关掉防护罩
That you can, sir, but I won't lower the screens.
我会在给联邦中央的报告中记你一笔
Your name will figure prominently in my report to the Federation Central.
史考特，你终于采取行动了
Well, Scotty, now you've done it.
没错，他们正在水深火热之中
Aye. The haggis is in the fire for sure, but I'll not lower my defences
但我不能因为那些甜言蜜语就关掉防护罩
on the word of that mealy-mouthed gentleman down below.
除非我能确认舰长的情况
Not until I know what happened to the captain.
要喝一杯吗，舰长？
Won't you join me in a drink, captain?
你会对我们的特雷雅感兴趣的
You'll find our trova most interesting.
我不是来喝酒的
I didn't come to drink.
我猜那就是你用来破坏
I assume that is what you used
12号裂解室的武器吧
to destroy disintegration chamber number 12.
这是把好枪，我不会吝啬使用它的
A very efficient weapon. I'm not afraid of using it.
我对你的第一印象是正确的
My first impression was correct.
你是个野蛮人
You are a barbarian.
是吗？
I am?
不要怀疑，舰长
Don't sound so incredulous, captain.
你就是个野蛮人，我们都是
Of course you are. We all are.
先是杀手，然后是建造者
A killer first, a builder second.
猎手、战士，说白了就是谋杀犯
A hunter, a warrior and, let's be honest, a murderer.
那是我们共同的传统，不是吗？
That is our joint heritage, is it not?
我们没有你们这么冷血
We're a little less cold-blooded about it than you are.
你想干什么，舰长？
What do you want, captain?
我要和我的舰队取得联系
I want to contact my ship.
我的通讯装置在哪里？
Where are my communicators?
在一个安全的地方
In a safe place.
你不要命了是吗，议员
You take a lot of chances, councilman.
你的心里只有舰队，而我想拯救一个世界
You're worried about your ship, captain. I'm trying to save a world.
如果我是你
If I were you,
我会想想怎么保住性命
I'd think about saving my life.
喝一杯吧，舰长？
Won't you have a drink, captain?
我们来谈谈我们的差异
And then we can discuss our differences.
我没兴趣
I'm not interested in discussing our differences.
看来你们似乎没有意识到危险
You don't seem to realise the risk you're taking.
我们不用电脑打仗
We don't make war with computers
也不会把人送到那种自杀装置里
and herd the casualties into suicide stations.
我们用的都是真枪实弹，议员
We make the real thing, councilman.
我有能力摧毁这个星球
I could destroy this planet.
你觉得我为什么阻止你联系星舰？
Why do you think I don't let you talk to your ship?
没有星舰我也能摧毁它
I don't need the ship for that.
你的意思是靠你自己和一把枪？
You mean, all by yourself with a disrupter, you can destroy this planet?
没错
That's exactly what I mean.
- 没想到你还有这本事 - 你以为我在开玩笑？
- I had no idea you were so formidable. - You seem to think I'm joking.
通讯装置在哪里？
Where are the communicators?
如果我说了，你敢直接去拿吗？
If I told you, captain, would you walk right out and get them?
是的
Something like that.
好吧，舰长，在作战室
Very well, captain. They're in the War Room.
左转，直走，再左转，那里没有护卫
Go left, down the corridor, left again. They are unguarded.
他还活着吗？
Is he alive?
真可惜
Pity.
像他这样的男人也许更希望能够战死
A man like that would have preferred to die fighting.
把他带去议事厅
Take him to the Council Room.
福克斯特使？
Ambassador Fox?
我是罗伯特·福克斯，阁下想必就是阿南7吧？
I am Robert Fox. Have I the honour of addressing Anan 7?
欢迎来到伊米亚，特使先生
Welcome to Eminiar, Mr. Ambassador.
特使先生，我对即将发生的事感到抱歉
Mr. Ambassador, I am truly sorry for what must happen.
你说什么？
I beg your pardon?
你和你的随从已被确定战死
You and your party have been declared war casualties.
你们马上会被带到我们的伤亡报到点
You will be taken immediately to one of our casualty stations
进行死亡登记
so that your deaths may be recorded.
你是说我们要被处死？
You mean we are to be killed?
没错，特使先生
That is correct, Mr. Ambassador.
我对此感到遗憾，但我别无他法
I regret it very much, but there is nothing I can do about it.
史波克呼叫进取号，请回复
Spock to Enterprise. Come in.
史考特，史波克跟我们联系上了
Mr. Scott, it's Mr. Spock.
我是史考特，史波克请讲
Scotty here, Mr. Spock. Go ahead.
- 星舰没事吧？ - 发生了一些意外
- Is the ship all right? - We've been through a bit,
但我们很好，舰长和你的情况如何？
but we're all right now. How about the captain and you?
舰长还没回来，但我们还没有伤亡
The captain is overdue. We've suffered no casualties among us.
请注意
This is important.
任何人都不许离开星舰，进行登陆
Under no circumstances shall anyone beam down from the Enterprise.
如果来到这里，马上就会被杀
They'd be killed the moment they arrived.
可那个福克斯几分钟前下去了
That ties it. That popinjay Fox went down a couple of minutes ago.
- 那个特使？ - 我就知道会出事
- The ambassador? - I knew it had a rotten ring to it.
将星舰开到相位炮最大射程处，等候命令
Orbit out to maximum phaser range and stand by for further orders.
史波克通话结束
Spock out.
你想怎么办，史波克？
What are you going to do, Mr. Spock?
找到那个特使还有舰长
Find the ambassador and the captain.
田村文书，你留在这里
Yeoman Tamura, you stay here
看着这位女士，别让她做傻事
and prevent this young lady from immolating herself.
该出手时就出手，这关乎性命
Knock her down and sit on her, if necessary. This is a killing situation.
尽一切努力保护自己，明白吗？
Do what you must to protect yourself. Clear?
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
你们要干什么？
What are you doing?
我可是星际联邦的代表！
I'm a representative of the United Federation of Planets!
特别代表
A special representative.
排好队
Get in line.
- 史波克 - 后退，福克斯
- Mr. Spock. - Please, Mr. Fox.
女士们先生们，请快离开那间裂解室
Ladies and gentlemen, please move quickly away
不然可能会被伤到
from the chamber or you may be injured.
你想做什么，史波克？
What are you doing, Mr. Spock?
进行特殊的外交活动，先生
Practising a peculiar variety of diplomacy, sir.
我会带你去避难，然后再找舰长
I'll take you to a place of comparative safety, then I must find the captain.
那些护卫说他被抓了
They have him. The guards told us.
他被带到了议事厅，有重兵把守
They took him to the Council Room under heavy guard.
特使先生，我相信你现在应该明白
By now, Mr. Ambassador, I'm sure you realise
一般的外交手段在这并不管用
that normal diplomatic procedures are ineffective here.
我不是军人，史波克，但我学得很快
I've never been a soldier, Mr. Spock, but I learn very quickly.
很好，多一个人多一份力量
Very well, sir. We need all the help we can get.
舰长，相信你应该明白我们的处境
Captain, surely you can see the position we are in.
如果你的人不到裂解室报到
If your people do not report to our disintegration chambers,
那我们将违反500年前定下的条约
it is a violation of an agreement that dates back 500 years.
我不关心你们的条约
My people are not responsible for your agreements.
你将对会毁灭一切的灾难负全责
You will be responsible for an escalation that will destroy everything.
数百万人将痛苦死去
Millions of people horribly killed,
我们的文明将毁于一旦
complete destruction of our culture here.
没错，梵帝卡星也是一样
Yes, and the culture on Vendikar.
灾害，疾病，饥饿
Disaster, disease, starvation,
惨烈的，无止境的死亡，痛苦还有苦难
horrible, lingering death, pain and anguish.
你好像对此感到害怕
That seems to frighten you.
任何有理智的人都应该害怕
It would frighten any sane man.
你说得没错
Yes, you're quite right.
还不明白吗，舰长？我们原本已经摆脱了这些威胁
Don't you understand, captain? We have done away with all that.
但你却令灾难再度降临
Now you are threatening to bring it down on us again.
难道你舰上的500个人
Are those 500 people of yours more important
比起数以百万计的无辜的伊米亚和梵帝卡居民
than the hundreds of millions of innocent people
更加重要？你到底是什么怪物？
on Eminiar and Vendikar? What kind of monster are you?
我是个野蛮人，这是你说的
I'm a barbarian. You said it yourself.
我本来只是打个比方
I had hoped I had spoken only figuratively.
不，你说得很准，我会证明的
Oh, no, you were quite accurate. I plan to prove it to you.
联系进取号
Open a channel to the Enterprise.
你让我别无选择，舰长
You give me no choice, captain.
我们不是绑匪，但现在我们别无他法
We are not bandits. You force us to act as bandits.
这里是联邦星舰进取号
This is the USS Enterprise.
史考特，2小时后执行常规指令第24号！2小时后！
Scotty, general order 24 in two hours! In two hours!
进取号，我是阿南7
Enterprise, this is Anan 7,
伊米亚最高议会首席议员
First Councilman of the High Council of Eminiar.
你的舰长、特使还有他们的手下在我们手里
We hold your captain, his party, your ambassador and his party prisoners.
马上让全体船员登陆
Unless you immediately start transportation
否则我们会杀了这些人质
of all personnel aboard your ship to the surface, the hostages will be killed.
我给你们30分钟时间
You have 30 minutes.
我是说真的，舰长
I mean it, captain.
如果是真的话，我就不用见证你们的末日了
All that it means is that I won't be around for the destruction.
我刚才下达了第24号常规指令
You heard me give general order 24.
进取号会在2个小时后摧毁伊米亚7号
That means in two hours the Enterprise will destroy Eminiar VII.
行星防御系统，向进取号开火
Planetary defence system. Open fire on the Enterprise.
目标离开了射程范围，议员
I'm sorry, councilman, the target has moved out of range.
你不能这么做
You wouldn't do this.
数以亿计的人…
Hundreds of millions of people...
这不是我挑起的，议员
I didn't start it, councilman...
…但我有义务结束这一切
...but I'm liable to finish it.
议员，我接到了梵帝卡的信息
Councilman, I received a message from Vendikar.
限定时间快到了，实际伤亡人数少了几千
Our time is nearly up. Our quota is short by several thousand.
他们在指责我们违反条约
They accuse us of reneging on the treaty.
看到了吗？已经开始了
You see? It's started.
你错了，这还没有开始
You're wrong. It hasn't begun.
议员，11号裂解室被破坏了
Councilman, disintegrator station 11 has been destroyed.
8号和10号隧道里的岗哨失去了联系
Guard positions in tunnels eight and ten fail to answer.
地球人曾出现在4-A长廊
Earth party reported seen in corridor 4-A.
你只有不到2个小时了，议员
You have less than two hours, councilman.
我的意志无法干扰这个进程，它是自动化的
What I want or don't want has nothing to do with it. Escalation is automatic.
- 你可以阻止这场灾难！ - 阻止？
- You can stop it! - Stop it?
我就指望它了
I'm counting on it.
接通频道，通讯官
Open a channel, lieutenant.
我是联邦星舰进取号的指挥官
This is the commander of the USs Enterprise.
伊米亚7号上的所有城市和设施
All cities and installations on Eminiar VII
都已经被我们的攻击控制系统锁定了
have been located, identified and fed into our fire control system.
1小时45分钟后
In one hour and 45 minutes,
你们星球表面将会遭到毁灭性的攻击
the entire inhabited surface of your planet will be destroyed.
请在那之前交出人质
You have that long to surrender your hostages.
谁来告诉我该怎么办？
What can I do? Somebody, please tell me.
别动！
Hold it!
过去，你过去，快快快
Over there. You, over there. Move, move, move.
现在，我们来谈谈
Now we'll talk.
我以为你需要帮助，看来我错了
I had assumed you needed help. I see I'm in error.
噢，我正需要帮助，去那边，史波克
Oh, I need the help. In there, Mr. Spock.
寇克呼叫进取号，请回复，史考特
Kirk to Enterprise. Come in, Scotty.
是的，长官，你还好吗？
Aye, captain. Are you all right?
我们很安全，你们先按兵不动
Everything's secure here. Maintain position.
如果一切顺利，十分钟后准备把我们传送回去
If everything goes according to plan, you can beam us up in ten minutes.
如果和我们失去了联系，则执行预定指令
If you don't hear from us, carry out general order 24 on schedule.
好的，舰长，还有什么吩咐吗？
Aye, aye, captain. Is there anything else we can do?
祝我们好运吧，寇克通话结束
Cross your fingers. Kirk out.
死亡，毁灭，疾病，恐惧
Death, destruction, disease, horror,
那就是战争，阿南
that's what war is all about, Anan.
也是为什么我们希望避免战争
That's what makes it a thing to be avoided.
你们让战争变得不再混乱、痛苦
You've made it neat and painless.
以至于失去了阻止它的理由
So neat and painless, you've had no reason to stop it.
这使你们的战争得以延续500年
And you've had it for 500 years.
既然只有终结战争能拯救星舰
Since it seems to be the only way I can save my crew and my ship,
我会帮你终结这场战争
I'm going to end it for you. One way or another.
- 特使先生？ - 怎么了，舰长？
- Mr. Ambassador? - Yes, captain?
可以把这些人带到走廊上
Would you mind taking these people
让他们老实待着吗？
out into the corridor and holding them there?
先生们，请
Gentlemen, if you please.
你过来
You.
奥斯本先生
Come with me. Mr. Osborne.
我们的通讯器和武器在哪
Our communicators, weapons.
跟我说明一下吧，史波克
All right, Mr. Spock.
这些电脑用于进攻，舰长
These are the attack computers, captain.
那一部电脑用于防御，而那一部用于计算伤亡
That one's defence, that one computes the casualties.
它们全都连在一部子空间传输器上
They're all tied in with a subspace transmission unit
并与梵帝卡上的电脑进行频繁的联系
which keeps them in constant contact with their Vendikan counterparts.
- 好的，继续 - 一旦这种联系被中断
- Yes, go on. - The moment contact is broken,
他们两个星球之间的条约就会被打破
it abrogates the agreement between the two warring parties.
你们想干什么？
What are you gonna do?
这一部是关键
This one's the key.
线路被锁住了，破坏它的话其他电脑全部会瘫痪
The circuit is now locked. Destroy this one, and they'll all go.
- 好，把他带走 - 不，等一下，不！
- Good. Get him out of here. - No, wait a minute, please. Please!
我们走
Let's go.
靠在墙上！
Against the wall!
- 你知道你都干了些什么吗？ - 当然
- Do you realise what you have done? - Yes, I do.
我替你找回了战争的恐惧
I've given you back the horrors of war.
梵帝卡现在会认为你们打破了条约
The Vendikans will now assume you've broken your agreement
你们将要拿起武器，迎接真正的战争
and that you're preparing to wage real war with real weapons.
他们会采取相同的措施，而他们下次进攻
They'll want to do the same. Only the next attack they launch
就不仅仅是电脑上的一些数字了
will do a lot more than just count up numbers on a computer.
他们会毁了你们的城市，你们的星球
They'll destroy your cities, devastate your planet.
而你们则会报仇，换做是我，我会开始制造炸弹
You, of course, will want to retaliate. If I were you, I'd start making bombs.
是的，议员，现在你们将面临一场真正的战争
Yes, councilman, you have a real war on your hands.
你们可以选择拿起武器战斗
You can either wage it with real weapons,
或者另谋他路
or you might consider an alternative.
终止战争，建立和平
Put an end to it. Make peace.
和平是不存在的
There can be no peace.
你难道不明白吗？这是我们的信仰
Don't you see? We've admitted it to ourselves.
我们是杀戮者，这是本能，和你们一样
We're a killer species. It's instinctive. It's the same with you.
就像你发布24号指令一样
Your general order 24.
好吧，也许这是一种本能
All right. It's instinctive.
但是本能是可以被抗拒的
But the instinct can be fought.
我们是人类
We're human beings
数百万年里，我们的体内都流淌着野蛮的血液
with the blood of a million savage years on our hands.
但我们可以抑制它
But we can stop it.
我们承认自己是杀手，但如今我们不再杀人
We can admit that we're killers, but we're not going to kill today.
你只需要明白这一点，我们并不是来杀戮的
That's all it takes. Knowing that we're not going to kill today.
联系梵帝卡
Contact Vendikar.
我想你们会发现他们同样充满恐惧
I think you'll find that they're just as terrified, appalled, horrified as you are.
并且不想面对终极选择
That they'll do anything to avoid the alternative I've given you.
和平或者毁灭
Peace or utter destruction.
由你决定
It's up to you.
作为致力于寻求和平
As a third party interested only in peace
帮助建立正常外交关系的第三方
and the establishment of normal relations,
我希望能帮助你们与梵帝卡协商
I shall be glad to offer my services as negotiator between you and Vendikar.
我在这方面有一点经验
I've had some small experiences in such matters.
这可能是个机会
There may be a chance.
我们与梵帝卡最高议会之间有专用频道
We have a direct channel with Vendikar's High Council.
- 已经几个世纪没用过了 - 那么它有很长时间被闲置了
- It hasn't been used in centuries. - Then it's long overdue.
我们过去吧？
Shall we go?
他们也许能成功，舰长
There's a chance it may work, captain.
- 寇克呼叫进取号，史考特？ - 在，舰长
- Kirk to Enterprise. Scotty? - Scott here, captain.
取消24号常规指令
Cancel implementation of general order 24.
通知传送室，准备接我们回去
Alert Transporter Room. We're ready to beam up.
让领航员制定前往阿加纳2号的航线，史考特
Lay in a course for Argana II, navigator. Mr. Scott.
参数设置完毕，舰长
Space detail set, captain.
伊米亚7号发来了消息，舰长
Message from Eminiar VII, captain.
福克斯特使说目前正与梵帝卡协商
Ambassador Fox reports negotiations are under way with Vendikar.
- 前景乐观 - 很好
- Outlook hopeful. - Good.
舰长，你冒了个很大的险
Captain, you took a big chance.
是吗，史波克？
Did I, Mr. Spock?
他们每年要杀害三百万人
They had been killing 3 million people a year.
而且杀戮延续了500年，但一场真实的战斗
It had been going on for 500 years. An actual attack wouldn't have killed
无论如何也不会杀死这么多人
any more people than one of their computer attacks,
而且还有机会让他们停止战争
but it would've ended their ability to make war.
战争将一了百了，不再发生
The fighting would've been over. Permanently.
但你无法确定你会成功
But you didn't know that it would work.
是的，这的确有一定风险
No. It was a calculated risk.
但伊米亚的秩序依然稳定
Still, the Eminians keep a very orderly society,
真枪实弹的战争是肮脏的事业
and actual war is a very messy business.
非常，非常肮脏
A very, very messy business.
我感觉他们会尽力避免，甚至寻求和平
I had a feeling that they would do anything to avoid it. Even talk peace.
感觉并不代表一切
A feeling is not much to go on.
有时候，对我们人类来说，感觉就是一切
Sometimes a feeling, Mr. Spock, is all we humans have to go on.
舰长，你几乎让我相信运气了
Captain, you almost make me believe in luck.
是吗，史波克，你让我几乎相信奇迹了
Why, Mr. Spock, you almost make me believe in miracles.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/